<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on Jarrod Linahan</title>
    <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on Jarrod Linahan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should haves; Would haves; Could haves; OR How version control could have saved my ass</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/version-control-could-have-saved-my-ass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/version-control-could-have-saved-my-ass/</guid>
      <description>So lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few projects in my spare time (Which, I might add, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of the past few weeks), and things have been going swimmingly.
I&amp;rsquo;m finally coming to grips with the intricacies of Java, and have a little Android app that is almost ripe for the picking.
I have also been getting down and dirty with a little Perl, having build a decent framework for a CMS for a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Current State of Melbournes Public Transport System</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-current-state-of-melbournes-public-transport-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-current-state-of-melbournes-public-transport-system/</guid>
      <description>Tonight after leaving my house for work I was thoroughly dismayed when I found that I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to grab my MyKi smartcard before running for the train.
I remember a day not all too long ago when this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an issue. You would simply buy a two-hour metcard ticket and be on your way. However tonight after fare evading on the country train I catch to the city, it was much to my discontent that there are now officially no longer any metcard machines in service on the CBD network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
