<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Jarrod Linahan</title>
    <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Jarrod Linahan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How probably not to secure SSH</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/how-probably-not-to-secure-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/how-probably-not-to-secure-ssh/</guid>
      <description>A past me apparently thought this was a good idea.
I think it was a minor modification on inherited shitshow.
This is only here for reference. Probably don&amp;rsquo;t try it at home.
It assumes you already have some kind of dynamic IP/DDNS thing set up.
Git history puts this around 8 years ago
 You should probably read this page instead.
 Dynamic host SSH access If your remote IP address changes between connections, the first attempt at reconnecting will fail and then spawn the below script to update allowed addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Sunday: RGB LED Power Consumption Calculator</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/rgb-led-power-usage-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/rgb-led-power-usage-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Before delving much-too-far down the rabbit hole of flashy, over-engineered lamp repairs and Arduino funtimes, I thought it advantageous to take an educated guess at the maximum power consumption of replacing some existing LEDs in a friends now-exploded lamp with WS2812 &amp;ldquo;NeoPixel Stick&amp;rdquo; clones.
  Num. LEDs   {{ bgcolor }}   Red mA Green mA Blue mA Max mA      {{ out.rgbMa }}   Red % Green % Blue % Total Bright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allowing only CloudFlare traffic to web server</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/allow-only-cloudflare-traffic-to-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 02:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/allow-only-cloudflare-traffic-to-web-server/</guid>
      <description>The other day I had a somewhat panicked client come to me, worried by threats of DDoS attacks by some rogue user. In order to reduce the attack vector in case said bad actor made good on their threats, I thought it might not be a terrible idea to disallow all HTTP(S) traffic that doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from CloudFlare. The client already utilises them for caching and load balancing, and their website claims that they are there to help in such situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pug templates with Sails.js</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/using-pug-templates-with-sailsjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 04:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/using-pug-templates-with-sailsjs/</guid>
      <description>For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been hacking on a few Sails.js based projects, my long-running pet project ZHDict being one of them.
After hacking on some Hexo themes, the first of which (which you&amp;rsquo;re currently looking at) uses Pug templating (the template engine formerly known as Jade) behind the scenes to render the HTML, and I&amp;rsquo;ve kinda grown to like it. You can think of pug as the love-child creation of Python and HTML after a steamy night of flipping bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressing PNG Images from the Command Line</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/compressing-png-images-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 02:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/compressing-png-images-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done gone and rebuilt this website once again.
See those little &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo;s at the top of each page? They are were the biggest files being loaded across the wire when you visit a page on this website. For the sake of saving bits and bytes, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d shrink the images dimensions down from their original size to the size you see them now (80 pixels2 × 2).
Starting out with a bunch of files that were 398 pixels2 , and after a quick bit of Google-foo, I discovered that my mac had a secret tool on it called sips - The scriptable image processing system</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Syncronisation with Unison</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/file-syncronisation-with-unison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 17:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/file-syncronisation-with-unison/</guid>
      <description>What was supposed to be a quick-and-dirty on 2-way file synchronisation for Debian servers using Unison.
   Pros Cons     2-way synchronisation May need to build it from source code   Exists in Debian repositories Not under &amp;lsquo;active&amp;rsquo; development   Runs under Unix/Windows/OSX More than 2 nodes Star topology recommended (ie, single point of failure)    Homepage: https://www.cis.upenn.edu/~bcpierce/unison/
GitHub: https://github.com/bcpierce00/unison
Manual: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grep in cPanel or Shared Hosting Environment</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/grep-in-cpanel-or-shared-hosting-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/grep-in-cpanel-or-shared-hosting-environment/</guid>
      <description>Being a command-line geek myself, it can be a massive pain in the ass not having SSH access to a client&amp;rsquo;s hosting service. Simple things like finding where a previous developer has declared some variable or template code can become what feels like a never-ending nightmare.
Never mind dear, PHP to the rescue…
&amp;lt;?php header(&amp;#34;Content-Type: text/plain&amp;#34;); // Replace $search with what you&amp;#39;re looking for // You could always make it a $_GET param.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jabberwock</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-jabberwock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 08:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-jabberwock/</guid>
      <description>After a little back and forth on the topic of tonight&amp;rsquo;s Language Corner, we settled on poetry and creative language. Both ideas were sourced from asking ESL learners what kind of content they would actually like to see.
At first glance, Jabberwock may not be the most intuitive piece of work to use in an ESL setting. The vast majority of the text is nonsensical gibberish. I think this poem could do well to help get students to think outside the box and attempt to express their thoughts in more creative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Subnet Mask Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/ipv4-subnet-mask-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/ipv4-subnet-mask-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>A quick overview “cheat sheet” of IPv4 Subnet masks.. This comes in surprisingly handy more often than I first imagined it would.
    Addresses Hosts Netmask Amount of a Class Class     /30 4 2 255.255.255.252 1/64 C   /29 8 6 255.255.255.248 1/32 C   /28 16 14 255.255.255.240 1/16 C   /27 32 30 255.255.255.224 1/8 C   /26 64 62 255.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe of the week: Freshly baked MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/freshly-baked-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/freshly-baked-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>A panicked friend came to me yesterday with a broken 15″ MacBook Pro (Early 2008).
I sat the thing down on my desk and hit the power button. The hard drive &amp;amp; disk drive made a bit of noise, the power light glowed faintly then CLUNK and it was off again. No glowing Apple, no hope of booting to Recovery Mode.
He repeatedly mentioned that it &amp;ldquo;must be a hard disk issue&amp;rdquo; so I swiftly replaced it, in the back of my mind knowing it was unlikely to fix anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js vs Java Play! Framework</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/node-js-vs-java-play-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/node-js-vs-java-play-framework/</guid>
      <description>After having somewhat of a heated Facebook conversation with a friend about the Ups and Downs of various web frameworks, I was inspired to benchmark a simple &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; to compare the speed and resource usage of Node.js and the Play! Framework (using Java).
Being mostly Perl guys ourselves, my go-to tool for web wizardry is generally the awesome Catalyst MVC framework, can&amp;rsquo;t say the same about my friend.
All the tests below were completed on my Laptop – Intel Core i5 M480 CPU @ 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Bit the Bullet</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/finally-bit-the-bullet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/finally-bit-the-bullet/</guid>
      <description>So, it’s happened. After a long time of falling into disrepair, the spaghetti code that was once behind this website has been swept under a rug (git commit; cd ../; rm -rf blog), and replaced with WordPress.
Hopefully this means that it’ll be easier for me to manage the content on the site, and will also inspire me to write a little more. Perhaps not – only time will tell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LNPPCF vs. LAMP</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/lnppcf-vs-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/lnppcf-vs-lamp/</guid>
      <description>Every day it seems that someone is writing introductions and reviews about how awesome using the so-coined LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL &amp;amp; PHP) stack is. I too was once a lover of this choice of software for getting things online, however over the past few years I’ve slowly replaced most of those with other free alternatives and haven’t looked back for a moment. This website, along with most others that I look after nowadays, are running what I guess you could call a LNPPCF stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert bytes to readable units in Perl/Java/PHP</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/convert-bytes-to-readable-units-in-perl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/convert-bytes-to-readable-units-in-perl/</guid>
      <description>I recently used code similar to that below in VPSMon, and came across a need where it would be convenient to display bytes as a more human-friendly string in Perl. Basically I’m building a script, and I want to convert the amount of available/free RAM on a machine from bytes to gigabytes for display to a user, but I figured may as well cover all bases and have this around in case it needs to display other units/multiples in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another year, another Android app</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/another-year-another-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/another-year-another-android-app/</guid>
      <description>So what better way to kick of 2013 than releasing something to Google play for all the other nerds out there.
The concept is simple – I wanna see live statistics about my SolusVM-based VPS servers, but the only other apps I found in the Play Store either didn’t do what I wanted, or didn’t work at all.
VPSMon is super simple, and gives you a quick overview of your VPS servers disk usage and bandwidth, and its current memory usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Didn&#39;t End</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-world-did-not-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-world-did-not-end/</guid>
      <description>It would seem that the world didn’t end on the 21st of this month, as predicted by the ancient Mayans, which means that tomorrow is still Christmas day, and that there is only one week left of 2012.
And man has it been a hell of a year. We’ve all seen a dramatic increase in the number of ‘memes’ scattered throughout our newsfeeds and timelines, danced way too many times to Gangnam Style, and decided that Aztec patterns are the new black.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McDonald&#39;s Australia Mobile App</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/mcdonalds-australia-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/mcdonalds-australia-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s official(ly unofficial)! I just released the first, and quite soon after the second, version of McRosters. This simple little app allows McDonald&amp;rsquo;s staff to easily access their rosters on Android devices, and also has a few other handy little features built in as well.
Now noone has any excuse to be late, as you can have your phone automatically set shift reminders and add them to your devices calendar or any linked Google Calendar accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should haves; Would haves; Could haves; OR How version control could have saved my ass</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/version-control-could-have-saved-my-ass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/version-control-could-have-saved-my-ass/</guid>
      <description>So lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few projects in my spare time (Which, I might add, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of the past few weeks), and things have been going swimmingly.
I&amp;rsquo;m finally coming to grips with the intricacies of Java, and have a little Android app that is almost ripe for the picking.
I have also been getting down and dirty with a little Perl, having build a decent framework for a CMS for a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shiny New Pie - Raspberry Pi, that is</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/a-shiny-new-pie-raspberry-pi-that-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/a-shiny-new-pie-raspberry-pi-that-is/</guid>
      <description>So although I may have missed the boat a bit, I finally got around to ordering myself a Raspberry Pi (model B) from element13.. Two days later, and it arrived at my front door - wrapped up snugly in a whole bunch of bubble wrap waiting for me to start tinkering.
So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a fairly functional XBMC/raspbmc set-up going, however I still need to find a powered USB hub to get my old portable hard drive to work with the raspberry pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting up and running with Nginx [CentOS]</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/getting-up-and-running-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/getting-up-and-running-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>While I&amp;rsquo;m on the topic of upgrading and installing server software, why not go quickly into how I get nginx set up on my centOS boxes.
It&amp;rsquo;s a super simple process as there&amp;rsquo;s an official RHEL/centOS nginx yum repository.
Basically, given a new server I would remove apache/httpd with
yum remove httpd Then create a file named /etc/yum.repos.d/nginx.repo and paste the configuration below within it:
[nginx] name=nginx repo baseurl=http://nginx.org/packages/centos/$releasever/$basearch/ gpgcheck=0 enabled=1 Then it&amp;rsquo;s a simply matter of running</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Perl from source</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/installing-perl-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/installing-perl-from-source/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve done this a few times now, and every time I go to Google to find the same article just to make sure that I follow similar, if not the same, steps.
You may be thinking &amp;ldquo;Ch&amp;rsquo;yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s just a simple configure, make, make install&amp;rdquo;, or a quick poke on the Yum stick, but maybe not. It is a good idea to keep &amp;lsquo;The Old Perl&amp;rsquo; (generally 5.8.8 as I&amp;rsquo;m a centOS sucker) as removing it via yum would remove a whole bunch of other things that rely on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access your Android contacts from your PC</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/access-your-android-contacts-from-your-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/access-your-android-contacts-from-your-pc/</guid>
      <description>The other day my phones battery went flat just as I was about to call a friend I had planned to meet up with. Much to my dismay, I only have said friends number stored on my phone (currently running Android ICS 4.0.4), however I had access to a landline phone and a PC connected to the world wide web.
To cut a long story short, if you have your Android device and contacts synced to your Google account, if you head on over to http://google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love Ice Cream.. Sandwich, that is.</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/i-love-ice-cream-sandwich-that-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/i-love-ice-cream-sandwich-that-is/</guid>
      <description>So, as previously mentioned I&amp;rsquo;ve just updated my Motorola razr to Ice Cream Sandwich (4.0.4), and quite frankly I&amp;rsquo;m loving it.
The interface has taken a minor bit of getting used to, but the fact that it is substantially more responsive, and umpteen times sexier have made the transition quite pleasant.
One of my biggest fears would be that my already average battery life would be negatively impacted, as I&amp;rsquo;ve read several reviews around the net about the ICS update for the RAZR that mentioned that it would in fact decrease the battery life of my poor little device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Gingerbread to Ice Cream Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/from-gingerbread-to-ice-cream-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/from-gingerbread-to-ice-cream-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Not a week ago I was trawling the web for info on how to jailbreak my Motorola xt910 razr phone in the hopes of upgrading Android from Gingerbread to ICS. I found a several how to guides, several ROMs and was pretty much set on getting on with it, however I got called into work before I started and since then haven&amp;rsquo;t given it another thought.
Then just moments ago, my phone sparked up with life and told me that an official ICS update from Motorola was available to download to my device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change centOS local timezone</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/change-centos-local-timezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/change-centos-local-timezone/</guid>
      <description>So today I was taking a look at those lovely lovely photos that I brought over to the blog from instagram, and rearranging some other bits and pieces, when I realised that the timestamps on said images were well off what times I remembered actually taking the photos..
So I took a look at what the &amp;lsquo;date&amp;rsquo; command had to say on my server, and low and behold it was set to an obscure timezone that is really of no use to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Current State of Melbournes Public Transport System</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-current-state-of-melbournes-public-transport-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/the-current-state-of-melbournes-public-transport-system/</guid>
      <description>Tonight after leaving my house for work I was thoroughly dismayed when I found that I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to grab my MyKi smartcard before running for the train.
I remember a day not all too long ago when this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an issue. You would simply buy a two-hour metcard ticket and be on your way. However tonight after fare evading on the country train I catch to the city, it was much to my discontent that there are now officially no longer any metcard machines in service on the CBD network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find user location using Perl</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/find-user-location-using-perl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/find-user-location-using-perl/</guid>
      <description>The other day I finally put up a simple landing page for a project that I&amp;rsquo;m working on. The site itself is fairly bare, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any features. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially the old &amp;ldquo;Under Construction&amp;rdquo; page, but with balls.
Rather than simply putting it out on the wild internet and forgetting it, I thought it would be interesting to log a few details about anyone who visits the page, to gather a few key demographics about people interested in the service such as their country and the time they spend browsing the site, among other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Am I? - Using Google Geocoding API with Perl</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/using-googles-geocoding-api-with-perl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/using-googles-geocoding-api-with-perl/</guid>
      <description>Quite some time ago I stumbled across a similar blog post to this one which detailed how to access Google Maps&#39; geocoding API to find latitude and longitude coordinates from a street address.
The process is extremely simple, and I just thought I&amp;rsquo;d give a quick overview of how the whole thing works.
So to start off with, the base URL for the API service we&amp;rsquo;ll be using is http://maps.google.com/maps/api/geocode/json?sensor=false&amp;amp;address=</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
