<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on Jarrod Linahan</title>
    <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on Jarrod Linahan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>McDonald&#39;s Australia Mobile App</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/mcdonalds-australia-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/mcdonalds-australia-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s official(ly unofficial)! I just released the first, and quite soon after the second, version of McRosters. This simple little app allows McDonald&amp;rsquo;s staff to easily access their rosters on Android devices, and also has a few other handy little features built in as well.
Now noone has any excuse to be late, as you can have your phone automatically set shift reminders and add them to your devices calendar or any linked Google Calendar accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access your Android contacts from your PC</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/access-your-android-contacts-from-your-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/access-your-android-contacts-from-your-pc/</guid>
      <description>The other day my phones battery went flat just as I was about to call a friend I had planned to meet up with. Much to my dismay, I only have said friends number stored on my phone (currently running Android ICS 4.0.4), however I had access to a landline phone and a PC connected to the world wide web.
To cut a long story short, if you have your Android device and contacts synced to your Google account, if you head on over to http://google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love Ice Cream.. Sandwich, that is.</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/i-love-ice-cream-sandwich-that-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/i-love-ice-cream-sandwich-that-is/</guid>
      <description>So, as previously mentioned I&amp;rsquo;ve just updated my Motorola razr to Ice Cream Sandwich (4.0.4), and quite frankly I&amp;rsquo;m loving it.
The interface has taken a minor bit of getting used to, but the fact that it is substantially more responsive, and umpteen times sexier have made the transition quite pleasant.
One of my biggest fears would be that my already average battery life would be negatively impacted, as I&amp;rsquo;ve read several reviews around the net about the ICS update for the RAZR that mentioned that it would in fact decrease the battery life of my poor little device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Gingerbread to Ice Cream Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/from-gingerbread-to-ice-cream-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/from-gingerbread-to-ice-cream-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Not a week ago I was trawling the web for info on how to jailbreak my Motorola xt910 razr phone in the hopes of upgrading Android from Gingerbread to ICS. I found a several how to guides, several ROMs and was pretty much set on getting on with it, however I got called into work before I started and since then haven&amp;rsquo;t given it another thought.
Then just moments ago, my phone sparked up with life and told me that an official ICS update from Motorola was available to download to my device.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
