<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>osx on Jarrod Linahan</title>
    <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/osx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in osx on Jarrod Linahan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 02:14:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/tags/osx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compressing PNG Images from the Command Line</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/compressing-png-images-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 02:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/compressing-png-images-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done gone and rebuilt this website once again.
See those little &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo;s at the top of each page? They are were the biggest files being loaded across the wire when you visit a page on this website. For the sake of saving bits and bytes, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d shrink the images dimensions down from their original size to the size you see them now (80 pixels2 × 2).
Starting out with a bunch of files that were 398 pixels2 , and after a quick bit of Google-foo, I discovered that my mac had a secret tool on it called sips - The scriptable image processing system</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe of the week: Freshly baked MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/freshly-baked-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrod.linahan.id.au/blog/freshly-baked-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>A panicked friend came to me yesterday with a broken 15″ MacBook Pro (Early 2008).
I sat the thing down on my desk and hit the power button. The hard drive &amp;amp; disk drive made a bit of noise, the power light glowed faintly then CLUNK and it was off again. No glowing Apple, no hope of booting to Recovery Mode.
He repeatedly mentioned that it &amp;ldquo;must be a hard disk issue&amp;rdquo; so I swiftly replaced it, in the back of my mind knowing it was unlikely to fix anything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
